There was a commission for this online magazine called Auto Strattle.
That was initially like a queer women magazine.
And they had like a series, like a summer series of writings that were like a people writing about pride.
And Eddler at the time named Sway Fam had reached out and asked me to do art for like this person named Benji's written piece on like the principles of pride and how there shouldn't be police pride.
And that's an idea like I had heard.
I knew about that idea because I had friends who were involved in activism around it like earlier in my life.
So I knew about that idea. And I got the commission.
I think right around like about at the time that George Floyd like was killed.
So I like got asked to do it and then made it like in this moment when more and more people were talking about the killing.
And I finished it and released it as just like an illustration to go with the article.
So why wrote and was like it should have the words we find safety each other.
It should have like this color range like I think so I gave me my color.
Palette that I use is usually like pretty pink and purple and other colors.
But so I was like we want it to be the blue like this like green is from there.
There's like a specific color range.
And then let me use a little bit more than that.
But those are the things that came from so why the editor and then I got to come up with the rest.
And I just thought like I want to do a version of like the cop car going into something else.
Like I'm pretty sure at some point I've seen like many different versions of people doing like what could happen if you had a broken cop car and like what else could grow out of it.
But I was like I think I want to do my version.
So I have just like these plans that I think do show up in a lot of my work or did show up a lot in my work.
And like want to capture like the feeling of beauty and peace even though like what you're looking at is like broken car.
Like also there's love.
Like between the two figures and also the flowers.
And so having a feeling of peace even though you're looking at something kind of destroyed.
So yeah, then the piece went out.
And it's been yeah, I think those are the thoughts I was having like I feel like I got.
So why told me some of those boundaries of like what needed to show up in the final piece and then I thought of the cop car image and then I just kind of like.
Spend three days in early June like just kind of moving stuff around in Photoshop and like thinking about what I wanted to look like and put it out there.
And then it's been like I don't get to know how it's used.
Unless somebody thinks to like tag me, but it was pretty cool like thinking because originally I thought of it as just like yeah just an illustration to go with an article but like something happened where like.
I think you just hit in a moment when people really wanted to talk about this when we were all like everybody was thinking about it.
And it seemed to just kind of like take off from there that I posted it and like saw it going everywhere it was definitely shared like hundreds of times from just me.
My personal stuff, but I also saw other people sharing it and I saw like the coolest thing I ever saw was like somebody sent me a picture of it like we pasted in like Sydney, Australia, which is a wild.
Like the coolest thing that I've seen happen by also saw it in like an abolitionist reader.
I was like, oh, this is going all over and it just started as like a regular illustration.
I like this really good friend named Tyco, who runs or is like part of running a press in Rhode Island called like bench press and Tyco.
I think bench press was doing a lot of like free printing for a black lives matter at the time.
They're like a it's like a community studio, but also they like.
Some day at the time were like producing prints for people like people could hire them to like do screen prints or like make them rees a graph art and Tyco themselves is like herself like a wizard of like.
He's like like using the rees a graph machine like just like total magic really good at it and like.
Like I feel like she like knew my she was already doing this work and she knows my since we're such good friends like she knows my actual like my true palette.
So she just was like, oh, what if I printed this with Rizzo and she's actually the one who changed it like just changed the fact of the colors that I normally use so that was totally her.
She came up with that was just like we will like she was because at the time I think they were offering anybody doing prints around black lives matter like related topics like they were offering them free printing so she was just like.
We'll print this for you.
For free if you want and so that's how I was able to like that's how that part of it happened and then they also kept it and have been like put it out with like some of their.
They do like a community print thing where they release prints in a big batch every year on a subscription, but also like they keep bringing it out every time new things happen.
So like they use it and I use it, but that's how it happened like that was just like my friend being like call likes hot pink like let's do that so that was totally tired.
But I still have a question I still have questions, live and I love to go deep into these images and I one of the things I've noticed in your work to is the use of kind of.
I see my cursor but the star like constellation symbols and I just wanted to hear you talk a little bit more about that because it seems to be so such a clear point of connection and relationality.
I think I'm just like a really like future oriented looking to the future type of person anyway and I think in like definitely the black community I feel like some people have that same impulse to like the best is in the future like look at what's not happening right now, but like what's happening in the future is where like the best.
So I think I don't know I feel really connected to like the sky and like star scapes as like something peaceful, something beautiful and something like kind of hopeful I would just like even if earth is like sucking like there's something about like the stars that feels good and it's like it's something that's like natural so it's like something.
I think I've been using them a lot to give my work like that feeling.
So much of the work in the images literally the work of you know finding a way for the planet and us to flourish and it's just this is such a classic of that it's in every way it captures that but I do think I mean it's interesting because we've seen a lot of we've seen a lot of police cars how we've
seen a lot of people's different and interesting ways like it's you know the way that the glass operates the way that the flowers are so much larger than the car itself and coming through you know there's just there's a lot there going on that's that's different to then what we've seen so it's a beautiful piece.
Probably you know just seeds is one of the spaces where a lot of this moves.
Do we have.
Yeah girls rock fillet I've worked with them before I think they asked me if they could they saw it and asked me if they could use it I was their design fellow that year and I hadn't made this for them but then they were like what this is definitely like we want to talk about this.
This is a different one this is a podcast but it looks like it's through the CUNY grads and.
Do you know where this is this is in New York I don't know where in New York this is like a friend of mine they were curating like five artists to make art I think about abolition but I'm not 100% sure and they asked five artists to send art that could be put up in like.
The band and like telephone boxes in New York it's like this project called art in add places in New York and so I took like the image and they just had me like reform at it to fit like the tall square and then they put that up so.
I never even got to see it because it was up like right in the middle quarantine but they put up I've never seen this before what is wait what is this so you can just put an image into reverse Google search right and so.
I put your image into the reverse Google search and I pretty much followed all of the links that used your image and this was just a PDF study guide for abolition and it's just a screenshot so.
I can't scroll through the study guide but your pieces right there on the second one which maybe that's like an an interesting time to to segue and and like ask you.
What does it feel like a not knowing where your work is showing up and in communication with us you're like well I don't know if abolition is really the word I would use and then it being on a study guide.
I feel like a person that's personally like really wants the world to be different but sometimes has trouble with like really believing that we can do it so I think that my art is like sometimes like my highest dreams are well the streams like.
What could we do like if things were different I don't even know if we can get this but I'm going to like make it make I'll just make the art about it but practically speaking like I think that's a place where I feel more stress so I think sometimes like I do find it's almost like the art is like ahead of me as a person sometimes and I feel like.
Sometimes I think very often I feel like I can make the art that says like what an organizer is trying to say.
But I feel like they're really the ones who have like the tools to like make it like they're working to make it so maybe if you ask me a question about like how I feel about it.
Then I don't know how to make up like I'll be like I don't know how to make abolition real and I live in Philly and like all my neighbors it feels like most of my neighbors voted for the couple of being probably incoming mayor you know and I think.
Like I don't want to have as many kids of our kids in prison but like all my neighbors seem to think that that's how it should be done.
So I feel like stress about the logistics of it and I just feel that impulse that I'm like I don't think that like a 16 year old should be in prison for life you know whatever you know I don't think they should be like thrown away and like I don't think that most of our families should be thrown away and I think this places messed up in the way that it runs like the country in general and relies on it I think it's like completely after and like.
I like abolitionists because I think sometimes like even if I'm stressed about like the how can this really practically happen like they're the people that care about teenagers that make mistakes they're the people who think that like tons of black men shouldn't be in jail they're the people talking about that like they're the people talking about how there is a connection between like people not having enough and then.
Going into a life where they have to take things because they don't have it I feel like that's more my relationship to the work yeah I feel like my main attitude has been like there's something in me that's like good at like imagining the feeling of like what would happen if we got the fantasy.
And making images of it and then like other people are very good at like taking that and using it and so yeah I feel like the use case of the person who used to in the slideshow in the moment when they were like talking about like the highest values kind of stuff like the feelings kind of stuff that is how it tends to be used and like that feels good to me like that feels like something I can do.
And it is really really exciting yeah I think it's wild and cool to see that like resonating with other people who are like kind of like dreaming and working in other places like that's amazing but yeah I did have kind of a while feeling because I'm like whoa like this is like in this reader like these people really think about this have thought about this on a deep level like well beyond what I'm feeling just like living the US for 33 years.
Like I have these opinions about it and what I observe but yeah I think that is something that I think where I'm like I'm an artist like and I kind of like a baby organizer and I'm not as like I feel like I know that I don't have the reading and don't have like the knowledge and sometimes don't have as much of the faith but like as I could but I think that like the art pairs well with people who are very good at it and I think for me in my learning it's like I'm like I don't know what I'm doing and I'm not doing it.
It's like good to be around like the Miriam Cobbos and other people who are like very good at the thinking like they have faith so it's like I feel like there's like a good like their faith feeds me I keep making the work we can work together to like talk about these ideas and like put them out there.
Yeah.
You know I think one of the things that we see the reuse is important because people are attracted to an image of something different they're attracted to see a world that could be different and I think your work is a real example of that in the fact that people want to use it so that's kind of our lead like we're trying to follow that.
So we do think that the artwork there's there's movement work that's intensive in so many ways but I don't think there are movements that happen without a sign and the signs are these so even that's my thinking with you that's on all this.
Yeah, I just.
A lot of my I wonder if you'll relate to this because a lot of my thinking takes place through the art and so when you said that it's almost like the art happens and then and then I'm like still thinking about it but it's already out there that really resonated with me like oh this.
This thing can be something that I am not and it can have a life of its own and exist.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, that is dead on.
That's it on that's it on that's how it is.
I love that that's like the best pieces when the pieces then like borderline this being a really good example but I've had one or two others like that but that's like if a piece can have a life of its own it's like borderline divorce from you it's not even a better.
It's not even a value it's turned into a meme and people are using it that's like peak and you actually it's true that you don't have to be you the human who makes it you actually don't have to be all the way to where the art is spirit to have that like power affect.
It's really cool it's like the fun is part of the job.